<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monitor on Bytes &amp; Words</title>
    <link>https://prajwalsd.github.io/tags/monitor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monitor on Bytes &amp; Words</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://prajwalsd.github.io/tags/monitor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Good monitor for a MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://prajwalsd.github.io/good-monitor-for-a-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prajwalsd.github.io/good-monitor-for-a-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time working on a code editor or a browser on my MacBook Pro (2017 model). Essentially all I consume at work on a computer screen is just characters mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the COVID-19 pandemic, I never felt a need for a dedicated work setup at home, but this one didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it was here to go anytime soon from our lives. So, I started looking for a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; companion monitor for my laptop. To me, the definition of the word &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; here was apparent — it should be able to render/display text very well, like really well, rest was a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious choice was to go for one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/sg_smb_5200/shop/product/HMUB2PA/A/lg-ultrafine-5k-display&#34;&gt;Apple approved 4K/5K Ultrafine family of monitors made by LG&lt;/a&gt; as a companion monitor for the MacBook Pro but my wallet didn&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of it. So, my hunt for this &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; monitor continued, and after weeks of reading (and watching tons of monitor reviews) I was convinced that a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; monitor doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist for my budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lg.com/uk/monitors/lg-32UN880-B&#34;&gt;31.5&#39;&#39; UltraFine™ UHD 4K Ergo IPS Monitor with USB Type-C™&lt;/a&gt; monitor. Although LG markets this monitor in the same family as the rest of the Ultrafine series monitors, the pixel density on this one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.displayspecifications.com/en/model/b9b81f2c&#34;&gt;~140ppi&lt;/a&gt; which falls short of Apple&amp;rsquo;s standards for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macworld.co.uk/feature/retina-display-3466732/&#34;&gt;Retina display&lt;/a&gt; on a computer screen (i.e. &amp;gt;200ppi) and even falls short of other Ultrafine series monitors produced by LG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build quality, USB-C, HDR10, 4K, ergonomic features, colour profiles, and the price point made the buy a bit more appealing than others in my humble research. However, I was still a bit worried about the main thing I was looking for in a monitor, i.e. a monitor that can render text very well, which ultimately came down to the display panel&amp;rsquo;s pixel density for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of hesitation, I decided to give this one a try, so I bought one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once setup &amp;amp; connected, at first, I thought this was a mistake and wanted to return it before I got too comfortable with it — the text didn&amp;rsquo;t look crisp the way I wanted it. But, truth be told, everything else about this monitor was excellent and delivered on the promise without a doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the context, macOS has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eizoglobal.com/support/compatibility/dpi_scaling_settings_mac_os_x/&#34;&gt;fractional scaling&lt;/a&gt;, which means your text is going to look a little blurry in most of the default resolutions available for the display and to compensate for this &lt;a href=&#34;https://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/387140/what-is-the-difference-between-the-different-font-smoothing-levels-on-macos&#34;&gt;Font Smoothing&lt;/a&gt; exists. Also, using 1x scaling on a 32-inch 4K monitor was not an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started playing with different display resolutions to try and see what mimics a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; rendering for this monitor given the distance from the eye &amp;amp; the viewing angle of my setup. After much trial &amp;amp; error, I felt&lt;code&gt;2304x1296&lt;/code&gt; resolution worked very well for my setup (i.e., at &lt;code&gt;1.6666...&lt;/code&gt; scaling factor). Oh, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thnkdev.com/QuickRes/&#34;&gt;QuickRes&lt;/a&gt; to try unlisted resolutions quite easily, by the way but you can even set it directly via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alphr.com/custom-resolution-mac-osx/&#34;&gt;System Preferences&lt;/a&gt; if you can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to install an app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did try the different brightness/contrast/sharpness levels in my honest effort to find my &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; setting, but the default values always did the trick for me in most cases. I think the &amp;ldquo;Mode 4&amp;rdquo; Gamma mode worked best to compensate for the overly bright whites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also explored various levels of Font Smoothing using a simple app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fontsmoothingadjuster.com&#34;&gt;Font Smoothing Adjuster&lt;/a&gt;, and to me default &amp;lsquo;medium&amp;rsquo; setting looked the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, below is what I settled on (to those 0.0001% of us out there who&amp;rsquo;re as pedantic on this topic as me):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolution set at&lt;code&gt;2304x1296&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamma mode set on &amp;ldquo;Mode 4&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharpness set to default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No changes to font smoothing (left it at default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lunar.fyi&#34;&gt;Lunar&lt;/a&gt; app to control the brightness/control levels automatically follow the MBP built-in display&amp;rsquo;s ambient sensor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been on this configuration for a while and occasionally rant about the blurry text on a few apps but I think this is it, perhaps I will some day find a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; monitor that fits my budget but for now I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
